[
    {
        "question": "According to the most recent classifications, there are only three oceans in the world. Choose the alternative that correctly indicates their respective names:",
        "answer": "Pacific, Atlantic and Indian",
        "options": [
            "Arctic, Indian and Pacific",
            "Antarctic, Atlantic and Indian",
            "Pacific, Atlantic and Indian",
            "Arctic, Antarctic  and Atlantic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What continent is the only one to span all four hemispheres?",
        "answer": "Russia",
        "options": [
            "Turkey",
            "Mongolia",
            "United States of America",
            "Russia"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "For an area to be considered a desert, what volume of rain must it receive a year?",
        "answer": "Less than 100mm per year",
        "options": [
            "Less than 250mm per year",
            "More than 2000mm per year",
            "Less than 100mm per year",
            "More than 500mm per year"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Grand Canyon's Rock Layers are predominantly formed by what type of rocks?",
        "answer": "Sedimentary rocks",
        "options": [
            "Igneous rocks",
            "Sedimentary rocks",
            "Metamorfic Rocks",
            "Volcanic Rocks"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Dublin North is located at what margin of the Liffey river?",
        "answer": "Left margin",
        "options": [
            "Right margin",
            "Left margin",
            "Southern margin",
            "Western margin margin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Certain places on planet Earth are home to more extraordinary biodiversity. Which regions have the most remarkable diversity of fauna and flora?",
        "answer": "Tropical forests",
        "options": [
            "Tropical forests",
            "Oceans",
            "Deserts",
            "Temperate forests"
        ]

    },
    {
        "question": "What percentage of the world's water do rivers and lakes hold?",
        "answer": "9%",
        "options": [
            "1%",
            "15%",
            "9%",
            "35%"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following events was not related to the Cold War?",
        "answer": "Spanish Civil War",
        "options": [
            "Spanish Civil War",
            "Korean War",
            "Cuban Revolution",
            "Latin American dictatorships"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which nation did NOT have a socialist government during the Cold War years?",
        "answer": "South Africa",
        "options": [
            "Albania",
            "Poland",
            "Vietnam",
            "South Africa"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Africa is divided into two large regions: North Africa and Sub-Saharan Africa. A sociocultural characteristic of North Africa is:",
        "answer": "The predominant population practices Islam.",
        "options": [
            "The small cultural diversity of the local native groups.",
            "Colonization of the region by Asian countries.",
            "Great social equality among the region's inhabitants.",
            "The predominant population practices Islam."
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the hottest desert in the world?",
        "answer": "Sahara",
        "options": [
            "Sahara",
            "Atacama",
            "Gobi",
            "Kalahari"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Africa has an expanding demographic landscape. One indicator that explains Africa's population growth is:",
        "answer": "The high fertility rate.",
        "options": [
            "Increasing infant mortality.",
            "Low life expectancy.",
            "The low replacement rate.",
            "The high fertility rate."
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mid-Atlantic ridge results from what kind of tectonic plate boundaries?",
        "answer": "Divergent boundaries",
        "options": [
            "Divergent boundaries",
            "Convergent boundary",
            "Transform boundary",
            "Subduction zone"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which tectonic activity formed the Andes Mountains in South America?",
        "answer": "Subduction zone",
        "options": [
            "Subduction zone",
            "Transform boundary",
            "Divergent boundaries",
            "Rift"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Listed below are the countries and their most polluted cities, except:",
        "answer": "Finland - Helsinki",
        "options": [
            "Russia - Dzerzhinsk",
            "Ukraine - Chernobyl",
            "Finland - Helsinki",
            "India - Vapi"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Countries located north of the equator belong to what hemisphere?",
        "answer": "Northern Hemisphere",
        "options": [
            "Western Hemisphere",
            "Northern Hemisphere",
            "Southern Hemisphere",
            "Eastern Hemisphere"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The continent with the highest concentration of fresh water is:",
        "answer": "America",
        "options": [
            "America",
            "Asia",
            "Oceania",
            "Africa"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What rock outcrops form the important landmark of Giant's Causeway in Northern Ireland?",
        "answer": "Basalt",
        "options": [
            "Diorite",
            "Granite",
            "Marble",
            "Basalt"
        ]
    }
]